Guide to the Bobbye S. Ortiz Papers, 1919-1993 and undated (bulk 1950-1990) RL.00978
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Phonograph Records Series, [195-]-[198-] and undated
  - Twelve Inch Recordings
    - Pop, Folk, Labor movement, Protest (Box 45)
      - #161 Title: Hang in There
        - Performer: Holly Near (Box 45)
          Side 1: Hang in There, No More Genocide, Oh My Beautiful Friends, Wedding Song, Birthday Children
          Side 2: GI Movement, Strong, Better Days, More Important To Me, Oh America, T'ng Dan Ta-Lu, Hang in There
          Record Label: Redwood Records, RRS-3800
      - #162 Title: Imagine My Surprise!
        - Performer: Holly Near (Box 45)
          Side 1: Imagine My Surprise, Put Away, Nina, Lady at the Piano, Fight Back, Riverboat
          Side 2: Mountain Song/ Kentucky Woman, You Bet, Rock Me in Your Arms, Hay una Mujer Desaparecida, Something About the Women
          Record Label: Redwood Records, RR401
      - #163 Title: Lifeline
        - Performer: Holly Near and Ronnie Gilbert (Box 45)
          Side 1: Harriet Tubman, Si Me Quieres Escribir, Beloved Comrade, Two Good Arms, Biko, Gracias a la Vida, Pastures of Plenty, Stormy Weather
          Side 2: Goodnight Irene, No More Genocide, Isabel, Perfect Night, The Activity Room, Hay Una Mujer, Singing for Our Lives
          Record Label: Redwood Records, RR404
      - #164 Title: A Live Album
        - Performer: Holly Near (Box 45)
          Side 1: Started Out Fine, Old Time Woman, Laid Off, Water Come Down, It Could Have Been Me
          Side 2: Faces, Get Off Me Baby, Free to Grow, Feeling Better, Haven't Grown Tired (of Living With You), Santa Monica Pier
          Record Label: Redwood Records, 3900
      - #165 Title: And Ain't I a Woman? (Box 46)
        - Performer: New Harmony Sisterhood (Box 46)
          Side 1: Sojourner Truth, Cotton Mill Girls, Ballad, Working Class, Ella Ellison, Draglines
          Side 2: Union Maids, Joann Little, 2 O'clock Lounge, Amelia Earhart, Unfinished Business, All Our Lives
          Record Label: Paredon Records P-1038
      - #166 Title: All the News That's Fit to Sing
        - Performer: Phil Ochs, Danny Kalb on second guitar (Box 46)
          Side 1: One More Parade, The Thresher, Talking Vietnam, Lou Marsh, Power and the Glory, Celia, The Bells
          Side 2: Automation Song, Ballad of William Worthy, Knock on the Door, Talking Cuban Crisis, Bound for Glory, Too Many Martyrs, What's That I Hear?
          Record Label: Elektra Records, EKL-269
      - #167 Title: I Ain't Marching Any More
        - Performer: Phil Ochs (Box 46)
          Side 1: I Ain't Marching Anymore, In the Heat of the Summer, Draft Dodger Rag, That's What I Want to Hear, That Was the President, Iron Lady, The Highwayman
          Side 2: Links on the Chain, Hills of West Virginia, The Men Behind the Guns, Talking Birmingham Jail, Ballad of the Carpenter, Days of Decision, Here's to the State of Mississippi
          Record Label: Elektra, EKL-287
      - #168 Title: Rehearsals For Retirement
        - Performer: Phil Ochs (Box 46)
          Side 1: Pretty Smart on My Part, The Doll House, I Kill Therefore I Am, William Butler Yeats Visits Lincoln Park and Escapes Unscathed, My Life
          Side 2: The Scorpion Departs But Never Returns, The World Begain in Eden But Ended in Los Angeles, Doesn't Lenny Live Here Anymore, Another Age, Rehearsals for Retirement
          Record Label: A&M Records, SP-4181
      - #169 Title: Odetta Sings Dylan
        - Performer: Odetta (Box 46)
          Side 1: Baby I'm in the Mood for You, Long Ago Far Away, Don't Think Twice It's All Right, Tomorrow is a Long Time, Masters of War
          Side 2: Walkin' Down the Line, The Times They Are A-Changin', With God on Our Side, Long Time Gone, Mr. Tambourine Man
          Record Label: RCA Victor, LPM-3324
      - #170 Title: Ain't That News
        - Performer: Tom Paxton (Box 46)
          Side 1: Ain't That News, The Willing Conscript, Lyndon Johnson Told the Nation, Hold on to Me Babe, The Name of the Game is Stud, Bottle of Wine, The Natural Girl for Me
          Side 2: Goodman, Schwerner and Chaney, We Didn't Know, Buy a Gun for Your Son, Every Time, Georgie on the Freeways, Sully's Pail, I'm the Man that Built the Bridges
          Record Label: Elektra, EKL-298
      - #171 Title: Morning Again
        - Performer: Tom Paxton (Box 46)
          Side 1: Jennifer's Rabbit, Mr. Blue, Victoria Dines Alone, The Hooker, So Much for Winning
          Side 2: Talking Vietnam Pot Luck Blues, Clarissa Jones, Morning Again, A Thousand Years, Now That I've Taken My Life
          Record Label: EKS-74019
      - #172 Title: Ramblin' Boy
        - Performer: Tom Paxton (Box 46)
          Side 1: A Job of Work, A Rumblin' in the Land, When Morning Breaks, Daily News, What Did You Learn in School Today, The Last Thing on My Mind, Harper, Fare Thee Well Cisco
          Side 2: I Can't Help But Wonder Where I'm Bound, High Sheriff of Hazard, My Lady's a Wild Flying Dove, Standing on the Edge of Town, I'm Bound for the Mountains and the Sea, Goin' to the Zoo, Ramblin' Boy
          Record Label: Elektra, EKL-277
      - #173 Title: Live at the Panacea Hilton
        - Performer: Red Shadow, The Economics Rock and Roll Band (2 copies) (Box 46)
          Side 1: In the Lobby, Stagflation, Commodity Fetishism, Hunger, Free Market Election Day, Anything Good, Movement Lovers
          Side 2: Understanding Marx, Gone Gone Gone, Ass with the Class, Rise, Hurricane
          Record Label: Physical Records, 21-005
      - #174 Title: The Force of Life
        - Performer: Red Star Singers (Bonnie Lockhart, Gary Lapow, Mike Margulis, Ron Rosenbaum (Box 46)
          Side 1: Still ain't satisfied, Sunshine silver mine, I won't go, Can't be free till everybody else is, Vietnam will win!
          Side 2: The belly of the monster, A women's health song, Pig Nixon, The force of life
          Record Label: Paredon, P-1023
      - #175 Title: Songs by Malvina Reynolds
        - Performer: Malvina Reynolds (Box 46)
          Side 1: The World's Gone Beautiful, Daddy's in the Jail, It Isn't Nice, Boraxo, There'll Come a Time
          Side 2: From Way Up Here, The Desert, D.D.T., Let It Be, Morningtown Ride, No Hole in My Head
          Record Label: Cassandra Records, CFS 5100
      - #176 Title: Chants des maquis du Vietnam
        - Performer: Madeleine Riffaud (compiler) (Box 46)
          Side 1: Avance dans la jungle, Marche de la libration, Le pal en bambou, L'Arme au chignon, Fille du Viet-Nam, Confidences d'un jeune soldat, Gongs des Hauts-Plateaux, Le printemps est revenus sur le Front
          Side 2: Air de xylophone des Hauts-Plateaux-- Arme l'exercice, Le printemps dans les zones de guerilla, L'arc de Y-On, Le mouchoir, Les oiseaux--Bombardements amricains, Indicatif et annonce de Radio-Libration, Musique traditionnelle, Les convoyeurs de riz de l'Armee, Nous cousons des vtements chauds pour vous, Louons la victoire de Ap Bac, Hymne du Front National de Libration du Sud-Vietnam
          Record Label: Le Chant du Monde, LDX-S-4316
      - #177 Title: Favorite Songs
        - Performer: Paul Robeson (Box 46)
          Side 1: Hammer Song, Water Me from the Lime Rock, Scandalize my Name, Jacob's Ladder, Witness, Stand Still Jordan, Takin' Names, Swing Low Sweet Chariot
          Side 2: Hassidic Chant (Kaddish), Wanderer, Songs My Mother Taught Me, Vi Azoi Lebt Der Keyser, The Minstrel Boy, The Orphan, Zog Nit Keynmol, Joe Hill
          Record Label: Monitor, MP 580
      - #178 Title: Cry of Vietnam, Three Vietnamese Voices That Cannot be Silenced
        - Performer: Robert Ryan, Cao Ngoc Phuong, Thich Nhat Hanh, Trinh Cong Son (Box 46)
          Side 1: The old man and the child, Lullaby, Madrigal of a girl who lost her mind, The Cio Linh mother, Nomads, A long day of sorrow
          Side 2: I'll go to see, A mother's fate, Vietnam instrumental music, The witness remains, Message, Vietnamese instrumental music, Condemnation, Peace, Going to see the country
          Record Label: Compassionate Arts of the Fellowship of Reconciliation
      - #179 Title: Le Bonheur
        - Performer: Catherine Sauvage (Box 46)
          Side 1: Tam di delam, La chanson de Margaret, Petition d'un voleur a un roi son, Le chant des vauriens, Mister Georgina, La manic, Le bonheur
          Side 2: Avec, C'est un air, L'echarpe, La Manikoutai, Les gares les ports
          Record Label: Philips, 844 743
      - #180 Title: Catherine Sauvage chante Leo Ferre
        - Performer: Catherine Sauvage (Box 46)
          Side 1: Vingt ans, On s'aimera, Ta parole, La chanson des amants, Les bonnes manires, La mlancolie
          Side 2: Comme Ostende, La grve, Mister Georgina, La complainte de la tl, L'ge d'or, C'est la vie
          Record Label: Philips, P 77.939 L
      - #181 Title: Penelope Isn't Waiting Any More
        - Performer: Peggy Seeger (Box 46)
          Side 1: Sweet Willie, I Built My Lady a Fine Brick House, Hanging Out the Linen Clothes, Poor Old Maids, Too Young, Housewive's Alphabet, Virginny O, You Didn't Do No Wrong, Jenny Bell, Darling Annie
          Side 2: Nine Month Blues, Good Girl, No More Will I Work in the Factory, Katie Morey, The Maid and the Horse, Song of Myself, Do Do Pity My Case, Talking Want Ad, The Housewife's Lament
          Record Label: Rounder Records, 4011
      - #182 Title: The Bitter and the Sweet
        - Performer: Pete Seeger (Box 46)
          Side 1: We Shall Overcome, Living in the Country, Mister Tom Hughes's Country Town, Where Have All the Flowers Gone, Barbara Allen, Turn! Turn! Turn!
          Side 2: Around and Around Old Joe Clark, Windy old Weather, Ram of Darby, Juanita, Andorra, The False Knight Upon the Road
          Record Label: Columbia, CS-8716
      - #183 Title: Dangerous Songs
        - Performer: Pete Seeger (Box 46)
          Side 1: Medley (Robin the Bobbin, Mary Mary Quite Contrary, Little Jack Horner), Die Gedanken sind Frei (Thoughts are Free), Jackaro, Never Wed an Old Man, Going Across the Mountains, Harry Simms, King Henry, Medley (Ode to Joy, Goliath Goliath)
          Side 2: Queen Anne Front, Joe Hill's Casey Jones, One Grain of Sand, The Pill, The Draft Dodger Rag, Mao Tse Tung, Walking Down Death Row, Two From Shakespeare (Full Fathom Five, Perchance to Win), Beans in My Ears
          Record Label: Columbia, CL-2503
      - #184 Title: I Can See a New Day
        - Performer: Pete Seeger (Box 46)
          Side 1: This Land is Your Land, Oh What a Beautiful City, Healing River, Follow the Drinkin' Gourd, Viva la Quince Brigada, Oh Louisiana, The Bells of Rhymney
          Side 2: Go Down Old Hannah, How Can I Keep From Singing, Mrs. McGrath, Mrs. Clara Sullivan's Letter, (The Ring on My Finger Is) Johnny Give Me, I Come and Stand at Every Door, I Can See a New Day
          Record Label: Columbia, CL-2257
      - #185 Title: Out of the Darkness, Songs For Survival
        - Performer: Pete Seeger, Kate Wolf, Holly Near, Don Lange, Chris Williamson, Charlie King, Jesse Colin Young, Dick Gaughan, Sweet Honey in the Rock (Box 46)
          Side 1: Old Man Atom, The Sun is Burning, No More Genocide, Take the Children and Run, Power
          Side 2: Acceptable Risks, Chain Reaction, As I Wwalked on the Road, Study War no More
          Record Label: Fire on the Mountain, 4001. Distributed by Kaleidescope Records.
      - #186 Title: Waist Deep in The Big Muddy and Other Love Songs
        - Performer: Pete Seeger (Box 46)
          Side 1: Oh Yes I'd Climb (The Highest Mountain Just for You), Seek and You Shall Find, The Sinking of the Reuben James, Waist Deep in The Big Muddy, Last Night I Had the Strangest Dream, Down By the Riverside
          Side 2: Nameless Lick, Over the Hills, East Virginia, My Name is Liza Kalvelage, My Father's Mansion's Many Rooms, Melodie D'Amour, Those Three Are on My Mind
          Record Label: Columbia, CS-9505
      - #187 Title: We Shall Overcome (Recorded Live at Historic Carnegie Hall Concert June 8, 1963)
        - Performer: Pete Seeger (Box 46)
          Side 1: If You Miss Me at the Back of the Bus, Keep Your Eyes on the Prize, I Ain't Scared of Your Jail, Oh Freedom!, What Did You Learn in School Today?, Little Boxes, Who Killed Norma Jean?, Who Killed Davey Moore?
          Side 2: A Hard Rain's A-Gonna Fall, Mail Myself to You, Guantanamera, Tshotsholosa, We Shall Overcome
          Record Label: Columbia, CL-2101
      - #188 Title: Young vs. Old
        - Performer: Pete Seeger (Box 46)
          Side 1: Who Knows, Bring Them Home, When I Was Most Beautiful, This Old Car, Ballad of the Fort Hood Three, Cumberland Mountain Bera Chase, Since You've Been Apart, Lolly Todum
          Side 2: My Rainbow Man, Poisoning the Students' Minds, All My Children of the Sun, The Good Boy, Be Kind to Your Parents, Get Up and Go, Declaration of Independence, Both Sides Now, Mayrowana
          Record Label: Columbia, CS 9873
      - #189 Title: No More War
        - Performer: Jacqueline Sharpe, Walter Raim (Box 46)
          Side 1: Love song, Honor our commitment, Lullaby, When I was a young thing, Drum majorette, No more war
          Side 2: Chant for the murdered, Mind your manners, boys, Cardboard apples, To the right--March!, Folksy rocksy sick and easy blues, I'll take my chances.
          Record Label: Cutty Wren, CWR 101
      - #190 Title: Sweet Honey in the Rock
        - Performer: Sweet Honey in the Rock (Box 46)
          Side 1: Sweet Honey in the Rock, The Sun Will Never Go Down, Dream Variations, Let Us All Come Together, Joann Little, Jesus is My Only Friend, Are There Any Rights I'm To
          Side 2: Going to See My Baby, You Make My Day Pretty, Hey Man, Doing Things Together, Travelling Shoes
          Record Label: Flying Fish 022
      - #191 Title: Viva la causa! Songs and sounds from the Delano strike. Por los huelguistas de Delano y el teatro campesino
        - Performer: Luis Valdez, Felipe Cantu (Box 46)
          Side 1: Ninos campesinos, Huelga en general, Ay pero si, pero no, Corrido de Cesar Chavez, La peregrinacion, Adelita, Yo no lo tengo miedo, De colores, Llegando a los files, Ser como el aire libre
          Side 2: Sounds of the strikers, El plan de Delano
          Record Label: Thunderbird, TR-00001
          Insert with transcription of the words (photocopy)
      - #192 Title: Together Again
        - Performer: The Weavers (Box 46)
          Side 1: Darling Corey, In a Jocular Vein, Get Up and Go, Tomorrow Lies in the Cradle, Wasn't That a Time, Dark as a Dungeon, Hay una Mujer, Venga Jaleo
          Side 2: Kisses Sweeter than Wine, When I'm Down for the Count, All Night Long, Something About the Women, We Wish You A Merry Christmas, Wimoweh, Goodnight Irene
          Record Label: Loom Records, 10681
    - Women
      - #193 Title: Songs From the Hearts of Women: Save the Children
        - Performer: Joan Baez, Judy Collins, Barbara Dane, Mimi Faria, Janis Ian, Viveca Lindfors, Odetta, The Pennywhistlers, Malvina Reynolds, Buffy Sainte-Marie, Hedy West (Box 46)
          Side 1: What Month Was Jesus Born In?, Money Crop, Legend of a Girl Child Linda, Universal Soldier, La Colombe
          Side 2: To My Countrymen, Vido Vido, Masters of War, Janey's Blues, Pans of Biscuits; Oh, Had I a Golden Thread
          Record Label: Women Strike for Peace Records, W-001
      - #194 Title: Songs of the Suffragettes
        - Performer: Elizabeth Knight, Sol Julty (Box 46)
          Side 1: Columbia's Daughters, Uncle Sam's Wedding, Keep Women in Her Sphere, Let Us All Speak Our Minds, The Taxation Tyranny, The Promised Land, The Suffrage Flag, Winning the Vote
          Side 2: Give the Ballot to the Mothers, Song of Wyoming, Going to the Polls, Where are the Boys Today!, The Yellow Ribbon, Hallelujah; Oh, Dear, What Can the Matter Be!, The New America
          Record Label: Folkways Records and Service Corporation, FH 5281
  - Ten Inch Recordings
    - Argentina (Box 47)
      - #195 Title: Antigua Melodia: Mlodie Ancienne, Folklore de l'Argentine
        - Performer: Atahualpa Yupanqui (Box 47)
          Record Label: Le chant du monde no. 547, 9361
    - France
      - #196 Title: Germaine Montero chante les chansons d'Aristide Bruant
        - Performer: Germaine Montero (Box 47)
          A la Villette, A Pantruche, Rdeuse de Berges, A la Bastoche, A la Roquette, A Grenelle, A la Glacire, A la Chapelle, A Montmarte, Dans la rue, A Saint-Lazare, Nini Peau d'chien
          Record Label: Pathe, AT 1033
      - #197 Title: Paris et sa Banlieue
        - Performer: Germaine Montero (Box 47)
          Au Pont de Charenton, Suresnes, La chanson de Bagatelle, Le Pont du Nord, Paris canaille, Neige sur la ville, Mon pot' le Gitan, Mouvement de valse
          Record Label: Pathe, AT 1039
    - General
      - #198 Title: Cancion del Pampino, La pobrecita - Zamba
        - Performer: Atahualpa Yupanqui (Box 47)
          Record Label: Le Chant du Monde, No. 548 Parte 9359/9363
      - #199 Title: Danza de la paloma enamorada, Basta ya (Ca suffit)
        - Performer: Atahualpa Yupanqui (2 Copies) (Box 47)
          Record Label: Le Chant du Monde, No. 546 Parte 9358/9362
      - #200 Title: Ya sabes mi Paradero, El pendon Morado
        - Performer: Atahualpa Yupanqui (Box 47)
          Record Label: Le Chant du Monde, No. 1002 Parte 6149/6150
      - #201 Title: Atahualpa Yupanqui
        - Performer: Los Calchaquis (Box 47)
          La tolderia, Vidala de la copa, Indiecito dormido, Chacarera del chaco, Camino del Indio, El Arriero, Atenita del camino, La viajerita, No se porque piensas tu
          Record Label: Le Chant du Monde, LD-S 4240
      - #202 Title: Ciel de Paris, la panse
        - Performer: R. Carosone e il Suo Quartetto, C. Bernardini, Geg Di Giacomo (Box 47)
          Record Label: Path, MG 218
      - #203 Title: Songs of Free Men
        - Performer: Paul Robeson (Box 47)
          Album 1: Oh How Proud Our Quiet Don, From Border to Border
          Album 2: Joe Hill, The Purest Kind of Guy
          Album 3: The Peat-Bog Soldiers, The Four Insurgent Generals
          Album 4: Native Land, Song of the Plains
          Record Label: Columbia Records, Set MM 534
      - #204 Title: Istambul, Ufemia
        - Performer: Bruno Rosettani e Quartetto Langosz (Box 47)
          Record Label: Durium, 10377
    - Italy
      - #205 Title: I canti della Resistenza Italiana, Ventennale della Resistenza 1945-1965
        - Performer: Coro Flymon, Luigi Molfino (Box 47)
          Lettura Motivazione medaglia d'oro con Inno di Mameli, Fischia il vento di Ignoto, Il partigiano di Ignoto, Brigata partigiana di Ignoto, Piet l' morta di Ignoto, Col freddo e con la fame di Ignoto, Egiustizia sar di Ignoto, Siamo i ribelli di Ignoto
          Record Label: Questo Disco
    - Mexico
      - #206 Title: Desafio, cu-cu-rru-cu-cu paloma
        - Performer: Tony Aguilar (Box 47)
          Record Label: Musart, M 1132
      - #207 Title: Himno nacional de Mexico: Mexicanos al grito de guerra, General Alvaro Obregn
        - Performer: Banda de la marina americana (Box 47)
          Record Label: Columbia, 5221-X (WP 23)
      - #208 Title: Aires del Mayab
        - Performer: Los Caminantes (Box 47)
          Side 1: Nunca, Ella, Quisiera, Peregrina
          Side 2: Flor, Granito de sal, Ojos tristes, Elrosal enfermo
          Record Label: Musart, M68
      - #209 Title: Mexican Folk Songs
        - Performer: Cynthia, Heraclio Cordero (Box 47)
          Side 1: La bamba, La llorona, Lucrecia, El palo verde, La voltereta, El arreo
          Side 2: Rosita Alvirez, Roman Castillo, El tecolote, General Felipe Angeles, Que linda est la maana
          Record Label: Vogue, CDM. 10.003
      - #210 Title: Maanita, Flor, Golorinda Viajera, Rayito de sol, Tu fuiste, El caminante del Mayab, Que lejos estoy, Menudita, Vol. 1
        - Performer: Guty Grdenas (Box 47)
          Record Label: Columbia, DCL 23
      - #211 Title: Cancion Mixteca, La valentina
        - Performer: Los Gavilanes (Box 47)
          Record Label: SMC Pro Arte, 2504
      - #212 Title: Pobre corazon, Mi preferida
        - Performer: Pedro Infante, Mariachi Guitrn (Box 47)
          Record Label: Peerless, 3193
      - #213 Title: Ojos tristes, peregrina
        - Performer: Quintero Mendo de Pepe Dominguez (Box 47)
          Record Label: Peerless, 2535
      - #214 Title: El soldado de levita, La raspa mexicaine
        - Performer: l'Orchestre Garrido, Trio Tariacuri (Box 47)
          Record Label: Typic, Editions J. Garzon, Disques Peerless- Mexique, 1041
      - #215 Title: A los cuatro vientos, El Mosco cacheton, Mama Lupita, Tambien te puedo olvidar
        - Performer: Rosita Quintana, Mariachi Mexico de Pepe Villa (Box 47)
          Record Label: Musart, M158
      - #216 Title: La malaguea (del film Enamorada), Cielito Lindo
        - Performer: Trio Calaveras (Box 47)
          Record Label: RCA Victor, 70-7474
      - #217 Title: La malaguea, Los arbolitas, La feria de las flores, Cartas marcadas, El crucifijo de piedra, Cielito lindo, Flor silvestre, Nunca
        - Performer: Trio Calveras (Box 47)
          Record Label: RCA Victor, MKL 3058
      - #218 Title: Los dos hermanos, La llorona
        - Performer: Trio Tariacuri (Box 47)
          Record Label: RCA Victor, 70-7535
      - #219 Title: Sufro tu ausencia: cancin ranchera, Yo: cancin ranchera
        - Performer: Pedro Vargas, Silvestre Vargas (Box 47)
          Record Label: RCA Victor
    - Miscellaneous
      - #220 Title: Corazn de acero, Fiesta jerezana
        - Performer: Carmen Amaya (Box 47)
          Record Label: Decca, 23228, Album no. 269, sides 3/4
      - #221 Title: Cuatro milpas, La borrachita
        - Performer: Los Gavilanes (Box 47)
          Record Label: SMC Pro Arte, 2503
      - #222 Title: Cielito lindo, La chaparrita
        - Performer: Los Gavilanes (Box 47)
          Record Label: SMC Pro Arte, 2501
      - #223 Title: La Punitiva: The Punitive Expedition
        - Performer: Luis Hernndez, Leonardo Sifuentes (Box 47)
          Record Label: RCA Victor, 46437
      - #224 Title: Caa: Popular Air, Zorongo gitano: Lorca tradicional
        - Performer: Manolo Manazanilla, Rosario and Antonio (Box 47)
          Record Label: Columbia, D.B. 3050
      - #225 Title: T, solo t: Canion ranchera; La chiquitita
        - Performer: Tro Calveras (Box 47)
          Record Label: RCA Victor, AA 488
      - #226 Title: S, s, s, no, no, no; Cielito lindo huasteco
        - Performer: Trio Los Panchos: Alfredo Gil, Chucho Navarro, Hernando Aviles (Box 47)
          Record Label: Coda, El Disco Supremo, 5013
      - #227 Title: El cascabel, Angelito negros
        - Performer: Trio Veracruz: Gonzalo, Prieto, De Vice (Box 47)
          Record Label: Pacific, 2756 M
      - #228 Title: La paloma torcaza, Dos arbolitos
        - Performer: Irma Vila y su Mariachi (Box 47)
          Record Label: RCA Victor, GY 816
      - #229 Title: Traigo mi, Cielito lindo: Cancin huapango
        - Performer: Irma Vila y su Mariachi (Box 47)
      - #230 Title: Songs of Freedom (Box 47)
        Album 1: Ya sabes mi paradero, El tragala
        Album 2: Marineros, Coplas del fuerte de San Cristobal
        Record Label: Keynote Recordings, K-128-1/2 and 3/4
    - Peru (Box 48)
      - #231 Title: La tana: Fiesta in the Scared Mountain, Tondero: Popular Peruvian Song in Flamenco
        - Performer: Carmen Amaya (Box 48)
          Record Label: Decca, 23227, Album no. 269, sides 1/2
      - #232 Title: Music of Peru: Ethnic Folkways Library (Box 48)
        Album 1: Pajarillo cautivo (Mestizo yaravi), Arza huamanguina (Mestizo marinera)
        Album 2: Achachau (Mestizo huayano), La Palizada (Mestizo vals criollo), Munahuanqui (Quechua huayano)